linkneel.com 2011-06-29

# Privacy Policy | CCIM Institute

**Privacy Policy for CCIM.COM**

1.      **Privacy Statement:** The administrator of the CCIM.COM websites ("THE SITES"), CCIM Institute. ("CCIM”) is committed to protecting the privacy and confidential information of the members and users of THE SITES. This privacy policy discloses the types of information collected, how that information is used to grant access to various portions of THE SITES, and the restrictions on the dissemination of that information by THE SITES. Any changes to the privacy policy are effective upon posting to THE SITES.

2.      **Types of Information Collected:** To ensure that only authorized persons have access to user supplied information on THE SITES, information is collected, and its access is limited, including:

2.1.   Registration. In order to use portions of THE SITES, a user must first complete the registration process. During registration each user is required to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which the user has expressed interest. In order to access the more advanced features of THE SITES, and to include and later edit their information on properties a user must be a member. We require a member to have a unique username and password to restrict access to confidential information and rights to revise or update information that member previously posted.

2.2.   Orders. A user purchasing access to THE SITES, or other goods or services from THE SITES, will be required to provide contact information (including name, billing address, shipping address, e-mail address) and financial information (including the card owner's name, billing address, credit card number, and expiration date). This information is not made available to any one other than the user's bank and THE SITES billing staff.

2.3.   Information. Users requesting information from or through any other source not owned or controlled by CCIM, which are accessed or referenced directly or indirectly through THE SITES, may knowingly or unknowingly provide information to the sponsors of those sites. The disclosure of that information will be subject to the privacy policies of those other sites, and not this privacy policy nor any agreement, express or implied, with THE SITES or CCIM.

2.4.   Legal Disclaimer. Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law when we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or legal process.

2.5.   Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable). We may share aggregated demographic information with our affiliates and/or advertisers not linked to any personally identifiable information.

2.6.   Third Party Advertisers. THE SITES may share usage information about users with reputable third parties for the purpose of targeting our internet banner advertisements on this site and other sites. For example, an advertiser on THE SITES may use cookies and/or clear GIFs, which allow them to recognize a user's cookie when a user visits their site. The information they collect and share through this technology is not subject to this privacy policy. For more information about our third-party advertiser or for choices about not having this anonymous information used please refer to the advertiser's privacy policy.

3.      **Who Has Access to Information:**

3.1.   User Consent. To access portions of THE SITES, a user is required to give certain information to ensure that user is authorized to access the information requested. The confidential portion of that information is accessible only by that user and the support staff who administer THE SITES, who are bound by CCIM's confidentiality agreements and policies.

3.2.   User Request. To fulfill a user's request for information, that user may consent, actively or passively, to have certain information sent to THE SITES, an affiliate, or a third party vendor to allow an appropriate response with the information the user requested.

3.3.   Suppliers to THE SITES. To provide users requested information, features, content, and/or analysis certain information about and concerning a user may be supplied to a third party. Users who do not wish to have those features can restrict access to their information by following one or more of the procedures described below.

3.4.   Third Party Intermediaries. We use an outside shipping company to ship orders, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services.

3.5.   Affiliates. Users and members may also belong to other organizations which are affiliated with THE SITES, with which we may share information on membership and use in order to grant a user or member access to certain portions of THE SITES. In addition THE SITES may have contractual and other relationships with organizations in order to improve the features of, and information within, THE SITES. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing those described items.

3.6.   Business Transitions. In the event THE SITES goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, user's personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via notice on THE SITES prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section.

3.7.   Supplementation of Information. In order for THE SITES to properly fulfill its obligation to users it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from third party sources, including:

3.7.1.      Credit Check. For example, to determine if users qualify for an extension of credit, we may use their name and social security number to request a credit report. Once we determine a user's credit-worthiness, this document is not shared with others.

3.7.2.      ID Address Verification. We may use third party software and/or vendors to verify a user's identity or address to preclude spam or other inappropriate communication with other users.

3.7.3.      Purchasing History. In order for THE SITES to enhance its ability to tailor THE SITES to a user's preference, we may combine information about the purchasing habits of users with similar information from our affiliates to create a personalized user profile. When a user makes a purchase or other transaction with an affiliate either of these two companies, the companies [we] collect [and share] personal [and demographic] information back with us.

3.7.4.      Enhancement of Marketing Profile. We may acquire third party marketing data and add it to our existing user database to better target our advertising and provide pertinent offers we think our users would be interested in. We use this information to enhance or overlay the "profile” of individual users. This aggregate marketing data is therefore tied to the users' personally identifiable information.

3.8.   Correcting Updating Deleting Deactivating Personal Information. If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information by contacting us using the means and addresses at the end of this privacy policy statement.

4.      **Means of Collecting Information:** In order to provide users optimal access and features, THE SITES collects information in several ways, including:

4.1.   Orders. We request information from a user ordering goods or services. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer's orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user.

4.2.   Use of Information. Users and members who post information to, and use information from, THE SITES are each given a profile which tracks and records usage. This enables THE SITES to verify that only appropriately authorized members post and edit property information. Profiles also allow the tracking of usage to assist in assuring users that the information on THE SITES is accurate and up to date.

4.3.   Profile. We may store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users and members. A profile is stored information that we keep on each individual user and member that details their viewing and usage preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of THE SITES for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to THE SITES. Your profile is shared in aggregate form only.

4.4.   Cookies.

4.4.1.      A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions but may cause portions of THE SITES to no longer be available to that user.

4.4.2.      By using a cookie with our site, users would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. For example, the user may not be able to become a member entitled to post or edit that member's previously entered property information. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

4.4.3.      Some of our advertisers use cookies on their site. However, we have no access to or control over these sites or the cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising.

4.5.   Email Sent through Sites:  Some sites (e.g., ciremagazine.com) allow users to email copies of articles to others. We retain logs of the sender's name and email address as well as the receivers to address possible questions of spamming.

4.6.   Third Party Advertising. The ads appearing on this web site are delivered to users by various advertising affiliates. Information about users' visit to this site, such as number of times they have viewed an ad (but not user name, address, or other personal information), may be used to serve ads to users on this site.

4.7.   Log Files. Like most standard web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer THE SITES, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to enable our Web-based service. We may use a tracking utility that uses log files to analyze user movement. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by THE SITES only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers or other affiliates.

5.      **Communications from THE SITES:**

5.1.   Membership Confirmation. We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username.

5.2.   Mailing lists. We offer several mailing lists for use by our members. Please see the Member Services area for information, terms of use, and instructions on how to opt-in and opt-out.

5.3.   Service Announcements. On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.

5.4.   Customer Service. We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes.

6.      **User Elections to Further Restrict Use of Personal Information:**

6.1.   Links. This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site they visit which may collect personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by THE SITES; this privacy policy does not apply to other web sites a user may access by or through THE SITES.

6.2.   Surveys. From time-to-time our site may request information from users via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose requested information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information may be used and/or shared with the survey sponsors. Survey information may be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Though we may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys, they may not use users' personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

7.      **Security:** THE SITES takes every precaution to protect our users' and members' information. When users submit sensitive information via the web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.

7.1.   When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL.

7.2.   While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Mozilla, Firefox, and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just "surfing". While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information.

8.      **Children's Guidelines:** We at CCIM are concerned about protecting children's privacy and follow these guidelines:

**THE SITES does not:**

8.1.   Direct its content or features to children.

8.2.   Collect online contact information targeted to children without prior parental consent or parental notification, which will include an opportunity for the parent to prevent use of the information and participation in the activity. Without prior parental consent, online information targeted to children will only be used to respond directly to the child's request and will not be used for other purposes without prior parental consent.

8.3.   Collect personally identifiable offline contact information which CCIM is aware is from a child without prior parental consent.

8.4.   Distribute to third parties any personally identifiable information which CCIM is aware is from a child without prior parental consent.

8.5.   Give the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information which CCIM is aware is from a child without prior parental consent.

8.6.   Entice a child to this web site by the prospect of a special game, prize or other activity.

9.      **Changes to This Policy:**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated in this privacy policy we will notify users via email and users will then have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with THE SITES, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that effect user information already stored in our database, we will post a notice on THE SITES notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we may also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

10.  **Contact Information:** Please contact: [webmaster@cciminstitute.com](mailto:webmaster@cciminstitute.com) with questions or concerns regarding this statement.
